[lively conversation.
gavel bangs]
We need to vote - now.
And I urge you all to remember.
my father and every headmaster
before him
protected this school
and its legacy. tooth and nail.
-Bloody freezing out here.
-I know.
But we can't go in till that
stupid board meeting's over.
They were supposed to be done
by now.
Even the council agreed. before
the Planning Act was overridden.
We should not sell this land.
[murmurs]
OK. I really do think
we should wait.
The vote is split down the
middle. so Vincent's vote will matter.
The headmaster knows
the vote is due.
It's not our job
to wait for him.
What do you think.
deputy headmaster?
He's not answering his phone.
Perhaps he's excluding himself.
I doubt that. it's his proposal.
Oh. for heaven's sake.
Let's take a 20-minute break.
then. but no longer.
-We've been here all evening.
-[grumbles]
The lights are still on.
[crows cawing]
What the hell is that?
[dripping]
No!
Hurry up and go!
[theme music]
You don't need to do anything.
all right?
Just be free for those two days.
I'll book it.
[Lola] Are you sure?
I have travel vouchers.
Will you just
let me surprise you?!
-[laughs]
-OK.
Gotta go. Lols. Chat later.
Oi! Reid!
[pacey. dramatic music]
This isn't school.
I'm not scared of you
or your little gang.
-Jesus! Bloody hell!
-Ow!
-What did you do that for?
-You were coming at me!
-I wasn't coming at you.
-You were chasing me!
-To ask for your help!
-Help?
Help with what?
People think I'm a murderer.
I need you to clear my name.
Ow!
[sighs] Really. Fergus? Is this
a new approach to clients?
He's not a client.
He's probably just in trouble
with a drug dealer or something.
-You heard of St Bart's?
-Yeah. I've heard of it.
It's a boys' boarding school.
very exclusive.
Yeah. an old friend of mine.
um...
Kevin Monroe
was the principal there.
Well. he passed ten years ago
and I think he was replaced
by Vincent something?
Quinn.
Last week. he was thrown out
of the top floor.
-Oh. so you pushed him?
-No. I didn't.
We'd a bit of beef.
He kept trying to expel me.
Ooh. what do you mean expel you?
You're not in that school.
I am. Now.
-I got a scholarship.
-Very impressive.
There's no way you got in.
You're a bullying little shit.
Well. from where I'm standing.
you're the one that clocked him.
He used to call me Weedy Reidy.
Really? That's funny.
No. I mean... it's terrible.
Really. it's terrible.
It's terrible.
Can you help me?
Why do people think
that you killed him?
I did some stupid shit.
all right?
Just messing. like. but...
I kept getting into trouble
with Mr Quinn.
Mm-hm.
So. when he died.
the police went straight for me.
I was in me form room
when he died.
I didn't leave it.
I swear on me ma's life.
I couldn't have killed him.
What?
[Charlie] From Jordan.
"Vincent Quinn."
Bruising to indicate
he was pushed
from the top floor of St Bart's.
They were doing some renovations
so there was scaffolding.
but he hit his head off
another balcony on the way down.
Instant death.
approximately 9:30pm.
His spectacles were missing.
they found that odd.
He always wore them.
They suspect they fell from
his face during the altercation
"and the killer picked them up."
Ah. Thanks. Jordan.
-Crime scene pics.
-Hm.
He left the school board meeting
at 9pm
after receiving a call
on his mobile.
The call came from the school's
internal phone system.
so they can't pin it down
to a specific phone.
All the boys were
in their form rooms. allegedly.
Well. he's unlikely to have left
an important board meeting
to go and inspect construction
at that hour.
Somebody obviously summoned him
to the top floor.
Yeah. Derek.
Well. that's not proven.
but I would be inclined
to check on him closely.
Kids these days. Ma.
they're a different breed.
and it sounds like he had cause.
There'll be a memorial.
I think we should all go.
My old friend's daughter's
still involved in this school.
We could ask questions without
deciding one way or the other.
This is a time of great sadness.
and while we are mourning now.
we must remember that St Bart's
is not just a school.
We are a community
-and we will support each other.
-It's Sherry Monroe. previous headmaster's daughter.
I believe that's her husband.
We should mingle.
[Sherry] My father was
very fond of you.
[Harry] And I him.
He was a good soul.
It's good to see that you're
still involved with the school.
Oh. St Bart's is our family.
-My two sons go here.
-[hum of conversations]
This school means
everything to us.
It's a tragedy what happened.
Did you like him?
Vincent. I mean.
Of course.
I heard there was a vote
taking place the night he died.
-Is that true?
-Mm-hm.
Vincent wanted to sell off
some of the school land.
and he'd brought half
the teachers and board around.
So. it was split
down the middle?
Mm-hm.
Why did anyone
want to oppose it?
That land had protected status.
Even the council
acknowledged it.
And it was used by the local
community. not just the school.
And then. suddenly.
it was overturned
and they decided to zone it
for houses.
The area would lose a resource.
the school would be flanked.
I mean. Vincent was like a dog
with a bone trying to sell.
Yeah. we're friends of the family. It's
great to see how well-loved Vincent was.
Yeah. Quinner. he was. er...
he was all right.
It's not true what
they're saying. though. is it?
That. er...
[whispers]
That Derek pushed him?
-Who's saying that?
-Everyone.
What was the story
between him and. er... Quinner?
Well. Derek. he was always
fronting up to him.
And as head boy.
I tried to rein him in
but they had a massive
blow-up that day.
Hm.
I heard Derek didn't leave
his form room that night.
Did he say that?
-So. you're in charge now?
-Acting head.
Sherry tells me that your son
is a senior Guard.
On sabbatical at the moment.
Does he have any information
about this case?
It's just. the board doesn't
know what to do
until the Guards charge Derek.
Or not.
He could sue the school if
we expel him during all of this.
claim that we prejudged
the outcome.
We have to be very careful. what
with him being a scholarship kid
and the fact that he's...
Poor? Disadvantaged?
Marginalised?
Oh. that has nothing
to do with it!
This school has always been
about equality
and giving
the less well-off access.
Derek has been
very welcome here.
Even Vincent said the sale money
would go into more scholarships.
Well. did you agree
with his plan?
God. no!
It's a terrible idea.
Putting profit over history?
Well. if the vote
was contentious
and I was the police.
I would be wondering
who was benefitting
from Vincent.
the casting vote.
not being there?
Look. everybody knows
that it was Derek.
That's why we're so eager
to hear what the police think.
I really think we should
just suspend him. Arthur.
-It's not that easy. Sherry.
-Tell her what he did that day.
He messed with the handbrake
on Vincent's car.
It rolled into the lake.
Totalled.
Well. luckily. Vincent wasn't
in it. but he could have been.
-Hi.
-Hm?
-Could I speak with you?
-Of course.
I overheard
your conversation with Sherry.
and...
I just think
someone needs to say it.
Derek's not a bad kid.
Well. he's misunderstood.
And. I mean. Vincent...
Vincent upset a lot of people
with that board vote.
I don't think it's fair that
people go straight to Derek.
If that's what
the police are doing.
Unfortunately. the police always
take the most direct route.
It... It's good of you
to. er. to speak up for him.
Yeah.
That vote seems to have frayed
a lot of tempers.
It has.
And...
Sherry insisted on having the
vote when Vincent wasn't there.
-None of this feels right to me.
-Ah.
And I feel so bad
for Derek's mother
coming here every day
with all this happening.
What about Derek's mum?
-[Fergus] Harry.
-Um... I'll leave you to it.
-Thank you. again.
-Yeah.
Everything all right?
Mm.
That's his first lie exposed.
Now. he left the form room
that night.
The lads don't believe
in snitching.
-But they did.
-A man was murdered. Mother.
Yeah. and why do you want him
to be innocent?
I just want him
to have a fair shot.
Why do you want him
to be guilty?
-Because he most likely is.
-Oh. I get it.
He tormented you. but you don't
know anything about his life.
I think Fergus has a point.
Whatever about his background.
the kid obviously
has anger issues.
Well. that doesn't
make him a murderer.
Look. let's not pretend
that you didn't grow up in
a nice little bubble. Charlie.
and despite our problems
with Marcello.
You both have had tough times
in your life.
but both of you
have had people who loved you.
And you. Fergus. you've had
people who gave you a chance.
Doesn't Derek deserve a chance?
No. it's not even remotely
the same thing. Harry.
-[Skeevie] All right. Happy?
-Don't do that. He's a bully.
I might have a bit of gear that
needs shifting. You interested?
Nope.
I'm out of that game now.
Stephen.
On the straight and narrow.
I had to hear it for meself!
So. Paula has you whipped.
And I've never been happier.
Oh.
[Malky] Once a toe-rag.
-always a toe-rag.
-[Fergus sighs] Jesus!
And there's you telling Paula you
are done with the dodgy dealings.
Now look at you.
chatting to Skeevie.
I'm just having a quiet pint.
Malky.
Maybe go home
and have a coffee. yeah?
[Skeevie] I'll be off.
Let's have no trouble.
[door creaks open. closes]
You're messing her around.
Nope.
That was you for years.
And you lost her because of it.
-Hey!
-Jesus!
Whoa. whoa. Malky.
Hey. here. Calm down.
What are you doing?
He's scum.
You've always been scum!
He's taking your mother
for a ride.
She can look after herself. Da.
[Charlie] Grab that.
I'll take him home.
-Oh. oy. oy. There we go.
-Come on.
That was my dad. growing up.
And I didn't become a bully.
People don't change. Harry.
And I'm telling you.
Derek Robinson hasn't.
But you don't wanna hear it.
Hi. this is Jordan.
Leave a message.
-[beep]
-Jordan. I need a favour.
I need to know
about Derek Robinson.
And I want a contact
for his mum.
[Harry] Thank you for being
willing to talk with me.
[woman] I'm happy to talk.
Sorry I have to do it here.
I've got to finish up.
-I have to get to work.
-I thought this was your work.
I have a second job.
You know your son. Derek.
came to my company
and asked for help?
The police will realise
he did nothing wrong.
Is that your experience
with the police?
That they always
get things right?
My colleague doesn't want us
to take this case.
Derek lied to us already
about leaving the form room
that night.
He didn't kill him.
I promise you that.
Look. my colleague also said that
Derek was trouble in his last school.
Boys aren't always easy.
And Derek's father...
was especially difficult.
For me and my son.
-Do you have any children?
-I have a son.
-His father?
-Absent.
-So you know how hard it can be.
-I do.
My boy isn't perfect.
but he has a good heart
and he deserves this chance.
As one mother to another.
will you help him?
I'll do my best.
[Charlie] You left
your form room that night.
-Where did you go?
-Who ratted?
-Oh. answer the question.
-We know you're lying.
This is stupid.
You sound just like those cops.
I thought you'd help me.
-Did you kill him?
-No!
It's best you tell the truth. son.
You did. didn't you?
Charlie. Fergus. stop it!
Sit down!
Derek. pick up that chair!
Stop ruining
my bloody furniture.
Look at me. young man.
I've met your mum.
She's a good woman.
she works hard.
A woman like that
doesn't raise an idiot.
even if you choose
to act like one.
[sighs] Look. I've promised her
that I will help you.
so I'm going
to take on this case.
but we're going to start
with the truth.
What were you doing
outside your form room
and why didn't you tell us
in the first place?
You're not supposed to leave
after 8:30 on week nights.
But the school doesn't
pay great.
so my ma had to take
another job.
I sneak out and help her clean
so she can go off
and do offices.
If the school found out.
they'd probably sack her
and use that as another reason
to throw me out.
I see.
But the pranks you were playing.
Totalling the headmaster's car
seems extreme.
It's hard to explain.
Well. try.
In me old school.
I made sure people were
too afraid to pick on me.
[scoffs]
At Bart's.
I thought I could change.
but me accent and me uniform.
being second-hand.
the lads had a pop.
I knew I couldn't
intimidate them
so I thought
I'd make them like me.
By being a rebel?
Why pick on the headmaster?
You must have known
that would be trouble.
He didn't care the other lads
were making things hard for me.
Quinn only liked rich kids.
He was the real bully.
[Charlie] He wasn't actually with
his mother at the time of death.
And even if he was. your
own mother is not a solid alibi.
I'm not saying he did it!
I'm just saying sometimes it's
more obvious than you think.
Go with the evidence.
[Fergus] We all heard him. OK?
He hated Quinn.
We need to look at that vote
over the land.
-There's something there.
-And how are we gonna do that?
Er... I don't know.
Charlie. shouldn't you
be getting home to Orla?
Mm? Oh. yeah. er... fair point.
[front door closes]
What are you up to?
[bike bell rings]
I could lose my job.
letting you in like this.
Once we get in. you go.
If we get caught.
we won't mention you. I promise.
Look. I told you on the phone
that we've investigated dozens
of cases and got to the truth.
I think that Vincent was
murdered because of that vote.
So. if you truly want
to help Derek. help us.
Yeah.
[lock turns]
Good luck.
[Harry] Where there's land.
there's money.
Where there's money.
there's greed.
Yeah. sure.
but what are we looking for?
I don't know. Poisoned letters?
Emails? Brown envelopes?
Yeah. I thought the land was
being sold for the school's benefit.
Aren't they building
affordable homes on it?
I mean. if no one personally
benefits. if that's the case.
it's a good thing. right?
Unless...
Unless what?
Unless someone very dodgy
is involved.
Guess who personally
overturned the Planning Act
to rezone that land.
Nicholas bloody Samson.
A woman in a dress like that
shouldn't open her own door.
Give me a second
to be a gentleman. won't you?
I gave you five seconds.
Then I got impatient.
[chamber music playing]
I had no idea you were
a patron of this charity.
Well. you know me.
I like to help the underdog.
I'm not sure I know you at all.
but I'm enjoying getting to.
Ooh.
-Great speaking with you. Nicholas. Let's talk soon.
-Of course. Good to see you.
[chuckles] Awful man.
Oh. Ms Wild. isn't it?
So good to see you again.
and such a worthy cause.
It seems we're both invested
in eradicating homelessness.
There's barely a project you haven't
put your personal seal of approval on.
Including. of course.
the protected land at St Bart's?
Sometimes.
tough decisions have to be made.
It's my job to make sure
that homes are built.
And will these homes
be affordable
or luxury developments?
I'm confused. Don't you want
people to be housed?
If so. you're at the wrong
charity event.
I just want you to know
that I'm still around.
So I see.
Did you know Vincent Quinn?
He was the headmaster
at St Bart's. he was murdered.
Strange how these things
keep happening around you.
What interesting things you say.
You know. I've been thinking
a lot about you recently.
Mr Kennedy. I must tell the
Minister for Justice that I saw you.
We're due to review your tenure.
aren't we?
Enjoy your evening.
So. we're not here
for the bad roast dinner.
If he tries to interfere
with your position.
-it'll be my fault.
-Please. Harry.
I know how to play the game.
But I get the sense
that he doesn't just play.
Think he had
your headmaster killed?
Well. I think they were
on the same side. but...
if Vince couldn't deliver
the vote.
I mean Samson's capable
of having him murdered.
But I don't think
that's what happened.
-That man is Icarus!
-Flying too close to the sun.
Ah. and I for one can't wait
to watch him burn.
[insistent knocking]
Oh. keep your pants on!
Sherry?
[Fergus] What's going on?
The police have been
questioning Arthur.
Arthur hasn't done
anything wrong.
but the board was about to vote
on him becoming permanent head.
I have to abstain
because of our relationship.
but with the police
interrogating him
and me not there
to speak for him...
But why
are they questioning him?
He wasn't with anyone. see?
When Vincent was pushed?
We'd taken the break
from the meeting
and Arthur wanted some air.
I was with the other
board members.
Well. this could be
a little difficult. Sherry.
We're working to prove
Derek's innocence.
But isn't the most important
thing to get to the truth?
I'm telling you.
Arthur did not kill Vincent.
He's a good man
and he's the best headmaster
that Bart's could have.
Well. for us to get to the bottom
of what happened that night.
I need to be inside the school.
OK?
Oh.
You mean
inside-inside the school.
[Fergus groans]
What?
Some of the other teachers
are aware of why you're here.
but for the most part.
the staff and the student body
believe that you are just
a substitute teacher.
It's very important that the boys'
education doesn't suffer. Ms Wild.
It's Professor Wild.
and can I assure you.
these will be the best
English lessons of their lives.
[phone rings]
If you'll excuse me.
another worried parent.
Of course.
Ah.
I wasn't expecting this.
Well. the police have started
to look at Arthur
so he was willing to oblige.
This is the best way for me to
figure out what really happened.
Look. I hate to say this.
but Arthur and Sherry do seem
like the most obvious suspects.
They were both vehemently
against Vincent's plan to sell the land.
Unfortunately. for the police.
that's still Derek.
He has a bit of a reputation
with them.
And he was a bully
in his last school.
He was a bully?
I didn't know that.
Well. that doesn't make him
a killer.
Oh. but it's still a surprise.
Would you... Would you like me
to show you around?
That would be lovely.
Yeah.
-[Harry] Very impressive!
-Oh. we do OK.
-Ooh! Percival D'arcy.
-[self-effacing laugh]
Chess champion.
-You were a student here?
-Yes. yeah.
And now you teach here.
Yeah. well. some would call it
Stockholm Syndrome.
[chuckles] Nine years ago.
Vincent was your headmaster!
Yes. he's the reason that
I came back. He was a great man
and. well. I was honoured when
he accepted me for the position.
I heard that his favourites
were always the rich boys.
-You must come from money.
-[uncomfortable laugh]
Well. the first rule
of money club
is that we don't talk
about money club.
-[chuckles]
-Shall we?
Yes.
This year's reading list
is very male heavy.
East of Eden. Nicholas Nickleby.
Ulysses. Ugh!
So. let's shake it up. shall we?
How about some Woolf?
Or Harper Lee? Or the Brontes?
-My father calls that chick-lit.
-[students laughs]
The Brontes were
literary geniuses.
They were so far ahead
of their time
that their writings
are still considered feminist.
politically
and racially astute today.
And all of that
while living a very sheltered
life in a parsonage.
never ever seeing the world!
-So. they were bored chicks.
-[laughter]
No one with a brain
is ever bored.
Their lives were very difficult.
Almost half the population
of their village
died before the age of six.
The sisters themselves
all died young.
Many historians now believe that
most of the village of Haworth
was drinking water that was
contaminated by the graveyard.
[students] Eugh!
Well. poverty and hardship
wasn't their only challenge.
The sisters had to use
male pen-names to get published.
Because. of course. the world
was dominated by stupid men.
And going by your
and your father's opinion.
not much has changed.
-[students] Ooh!
-[laughter]
So. shall we ditch
the navel-gazing of Ulysses
and visit the mad woman in the
attic of Jane Eyre. shall we?
[knock on window]
How did the police
miss evidence?
I don't know.
but Vicky told Charlie
that they've found something
and they believe
it's significant.
They've taken some of these
blue chips as evidence.
It's like the killer
put his foot up. like this.
And used it as leverage
to push Vincent over?
Yeah.
Do the police know
where the blue paint came from?
Mm-hm.
Some people might feel this way
about Yeats
but I. for one. have always
found him fascinating.
"An aged man
is but a paltry thing.
a tattered coat upon a stick."
But wait. perhaps this isn't
your reflection on the poetry.
It's a... self-portrait?
[laughter]
Less arse. more art.
Hm.
"Yeats. a man willing to examine
and eviscerate himself
at every turn without fear
or censorship.
to give of himself
these glorious words."
This is beautiful.
What's your name?
Peter. Miss.
Alexander. you should read
Peter's essay.
-You might learn something.
-I don't need to read his essay.
Headmaster Quinn
personally chose me
for the annual
essay-writing competition.
Did the headmaster
ever comment on your work?
Well. you're the one that should
be submitting your work
for that competition.
You have a way with words.
-Ssh!
-[laughter]
[school bell rings]
[Harry] I am getting
the distinct impression
that Vincent wasn't
the fairest of headmasters.
Telling me the truth won't
make me think you're guilty.
Vincent could be narrow-sighted.
He thought that some boys needed
more pressure than others.
Let me guess. the poor ones?
-Huh.
-Was he a bully?
Did he torment Derek
or the other kids?
Well. that's the problem.
If he was doing something outright.
something you could put your finger on.
But he wasn't.
And there are many boys
and teachers
and parents associated
with this school
who feel that Vincent
was a brilliant head.
That just means
he was a clever bully. Arthur.
and nobody here
was willing to catch him out.
I guess you're right.
[phone buzzes]
Hello?
[distorted voice]
Back off. you stupid bitch.
-That cape fools nobody.
-Who is this?
You're not even a real teacher.
Keep asking questions
and see what happens to you.
[call ends]
[beep]
I'm fine. it takes more than
that to scare me.
[Fergus] Look. you're obviously
asking the right questions.
but I'm not sure about you being
in there on your own. Harry.
Well. what are you suggesting?
We smuggle you in as a student?
Hell. no!
I had enough of real school.
I'm barely able for lectures.
[unclear banter]
I have to call you back. Fergus.
If you're going to get a pair of fake trainers.
at least get a pair that can pass muster.
-Just give it a rest. Tobias.
-Do what your master says. will ya?
-I'm just trying to help out. pal.
-Pal? I'm not your pal.
I can't stay here. mate. What makes
you think you can speak to me like that?
-What? Speak to you like what...
-Everything OK here?
Just messing around. miss.
Well. try messing around
with someone else.
[floorboards creak]
[tense music]
Ooh!
Hello?
Hello!
Really. Ma? You're doing
undercover work now?
Keep up. I've done it loads. it
works and I'm learning things.
Yeah. like how to get locked in.
You can't stay here. If you're
right and Derek didn't do this...
I'm right.
Then the real killer
is obviously onto you.
Oh. number one.
I am staying here. Number two.
take out both your phones.
Specifically. the photographs
of the crime scene.
Is that from the first set
that Jordan sent?
Yes.
Fergus. I need the second set
that Jordan sent.
the one you showed me
with the paint on the rail.
-Here.
-Hm.
That paint wasn't there
when they first examined
the crime scene.
-Somebody put it there.
-Shit! Why?
To frame Derek Robinson.
Those were his shoes.
You need to let Jordan know
this is a ploy.
[phone beeps. ringing]
-Hup.
-[Harry] Excuse me?
I. er. I believe you're the boys
that told this gentleman
that Derek left his form room the night
that your headmaster was murdered?
-Yeah.
-And?
Well. and you drew attention
to the fact that his trainers
were fake
and there was blue paint
coming off of them.
Yeah. so what?
Well. it's almost like
you want him to be in trouble.
We shouldn't have to go
to a school with kids like that.
Do you know how much my father
pays for me to go here?
I think the relevant information
there is that it's your father paying.
-Excuse me. but who are you?
-OK. Tobias. mate... chill.
We're sorry about that.
We're just kidding.
We understand
how serious all of this is.
I'm glad to hear that.
So. did the police
ask you any questions
about where you were
the night your headmaster died?
Oh. our... our parents wouldn't
allow us to be questioned.
It's crazy. that. We liked him.
We could have just
pushed him off for fun.
and made sure Derek
took the blame.
[both laugh out loud]
But of course we'd never
do that. but if we did...
If we did. our parents would make
sure we were never held to account.
I'm sure you'll find that Mummy
and Daddy can only do so much.
Money doesn't buy you
everything.
It'll buy us futures
outside of this place.
We won't be stuck like those
paupers who end up working here.
-What paupers?
-The scholarship kids.
They all end up teaching here
in the end.
Nowhere else will have them.
Which teachers?
-Half of them.
-Mm.
-D'arcy. Rowe.
-Yeah.
-Mr Loomes.
-[both snigger]
What's it they say?
"Those who can't do. teach."
You could say the same for those
who come here on scholarships.
I mean. it's true. isn't it?
You know.
I never thought I'd say this.
but I really hope
you're right about Derek
and it's one of those two
who go down.
All right. Harry?
You still with me?
Oh. sorry.
I have to go to class.
I promised Arthur that I'd give
these boys an education.
I've got to go.
OK. Bye so?
Guess I'll make my own way out.
[Harry] "'Sit down. beggar!'"
screamed Squeers.
almost beside himself with rage
and seizing Smike as he spoke.
'Wretch. ' rejoined Nicholas. fiercely.
'Touch him at your peril!
I will not stand by.
and see it done.
My blood is up. and I have the
strength of ten such men as you.
Look to yourself. for Heaven
I will not spare you.
if you drive me on!'
'Stand back. ' cried Squeers.
brandishing his weapon.
'I have a long series of insults
to avenge. '
said Nicholas.
flushed with passion.
'and my indignation
is aggravated
by the dastardly cruelties
practised
on helpless infancy
in this foul den.
Have a care;
for if you do raise
the devil within me.
"the consequences shall fall
heavily upon your own head.'"
Fergus. I think I know what
happened. but I need evidence.
And get Charlie. We need a plan.
[Jordan] I just wanted
to update you all
on the current state
of the case.
Now. as you may know.
we found what we believed to be
some evidence
where Mr Quinn was pushed.
However. the Director
of Public Prosecutions
doesn't believe it's substantial
enough to issue a warrant.
We're now considering the land
sale as the primary motive.
That is nonsense.
We all know who did this.
When are you going
to arrest him?
-Sherry!
-There is a strong suspect.
but we need more evidence
and for now. we have to keep
our options open.
Mr Rowe. I wanted to reinterview
you. if that's all right.
You're meant to be helping him.
It's obvious
that Derek did this.
And it's obvious
that they need proof.
[huffs]
Caught in the act.
Percival.
Planting evidence
that only the killer could have.
I presume you took these
as security.
in case you needed
to frame somebody.
-[Percival] This is a mistake.
-The mistake's not realising
we searched your room earlier
and discovered these glasses.
owned by the victim.
but we left them in place
so that you could do exactly
what you just tried to do.
Nicholas Nickleby.
that's when I realised.
You were a scholarship
student here.
but you were bullied by Vincent.
You didn't come here
because of Stockholm Syndrome.
You came here
because you wanted revenge.
And you didn't know
how to go about it.
But then you saw Vincent picking
on other kids. especially Derek.
That day. Derek pulled
the prank of all pranks.
totalling Vincent's car.
and Vincent lost it.
And you saw the equivalent of
the cruel headmaster in Nickleby
caning Smike.
and something in you snapped.
I did this to help Derek
and all the others.
This was self-defence.
I... I swear.
Vincent made my life hell when
he started here as headmaster.
But why let Derek
take the blame?
Well. I hadn't planned to but then when I
found out he was a bully in his last school.
he was no better
than the others.
Everybody in life
has been bullied. Percival.
But if you'd just lashed out
at yours.
this would seem understandable.
But to frame a child?
You're the one
that's no better than Vincent.
What the hell would you know?
With your plummy accent
and your fancy college job!
You've no idea
what I've overcome.
-[sirens approaching]
-No idea!
-[handcuffs click]
-Stupid bitch!
-You should have stayed away when I warned you...
-That'll do!
Come on.
[owl hoots]
Me ma wanted to say
thanks as well.
Well. you're very welcome.
You both are.
And I wanted to say sorry for...
you know.
being a little git in school.
Don't worry about it. pal.
Plus. you were never little.
-[chuckles]
-I mean it.
From the bottom of my heart.
There's not many people
that stuck up for Derek.
-I wish we could pay you back.
-He can.
Do brilliantly in your life.
Derek. I'll be watching.
Not sure if they'll let me stay.
Ah. they will.
Just make them see
that it's worth it. yeah?
[Arthur] Derek?
OK. I'm sorry.
You were right about him.
-I'm always right.
-And yet you liked Percival.
-Didn't you?
-Oh. no. not at all.
-I found him intolerable.
-[laughs]
-Time to rain on their parade.
-Oh. absolutely.
Told you. it's always the scholarship
ones that cause the problems.
Not quite.
Not your problems. anyway.
What problems?
Oh. we had a few hours
to kill earlier.
[Harry] And we were
very productive with our time.
We passed every one of your
essays through an AI check.
[Fergus] Turns out. you've been
cheating for a whole year.
Mm. your headmaster is furious.
He wants you to rewrite
everything before the exams.
Which are in three weeks. right?
Mummy and Daddy can't get you
out of this one.
[Harry] I'm proud of you.
Fergus.
It takes a lot of strength
to let go of old grievances.
Yeah. well. I still wouldn't
want to meet him in a dark alley.
I wouldn't want to meet anyone
in a dark alley.
I meet some of best contacts
in dark alleys.
[Charlie laughs]
-You OK?
-Absolutely.
I just need to make
a quick call.
And afterwards.
may I take you out for dinner?
-Oh. it's my turn.
-Mm. like I said.
let me be a gentleman
for a second?
OK. OK. you can treat me.
All right.
[Fergus] Well. you look
very happy.
I am.
Very much so.
[theme music]